KIRSI **RALKO**

PO Box 2230, Kenora ON P9N 3X8 · (807) 464-0687 kirsiralko@gmail.com · www.kenorafamilylaw.com

SUMMARY

Litigation lawyer and business owner pursuing new challenges in the tech field. I am seeking a role that allows me to apply what I've learned in university and the last 5 years in the workforce to a job in coding/development.

Skilled in written communication, research, public speaking and logical reasoning.

EXPERIENCE

JULY 2019 - PRESENT

LAWYER/OWNER, KIRSI RALKO BARRISTER & SOLICITOR

I am currently the owner of a solo practice established July 2019. Primary focus on Family Law, both litigation and non-litigation. Commencing in July 2020 I also resumed handling residential real estate transactions.

DECEMBER 2018 – PRESENT CITY COUNCILLOR, CITY OF KENORA

Elected as Councillor At Large for the City of Kenora, 2018 to 2022 term.

Boards and Committees related to this role:

- Harbourtown BIZ (Business Improvement Area) Committee Council Representative
- Association of Municipalities of Ontario (AMO) Youth Advisory Council
- Economic Development Commission Council Representative (Alternate)
- Kenora Public Library Board of Directors Council Representative (Alternate)
- Women in Politics in Northwestern Ontario Committee

APRIL 2014 - JUNE 2019

SHEWCHUK, ORMISTON, RICHARDT & JOHNSON LLP

ASSOCIATE LAWYER, JUNE 2016 – JUNE 2019

ARTICLING STUDENT, JUNE 2015 – JUNE 2016

SUMMER STUDENT, APRIL 2014 – AUGUST 2014

As a student, I assisted with files of all types including both litigation and solicitor's work. My practice as an associate was primarily focussed on Family and Civil litigation, with some involvement in Real Estate transactions.

OCTOBER 2017 – OCTOBER 2019 OWNER, 1885 WINE & WHISKY ROOM

Co-owner and President of an Ontario corporation operating in Kenora, ON as 1885 Wine & Whisky Room, a wine/whisky bar and art gallery focussed on showcasing local artists and musicians. Responsible for business finances, payroll, and inventory.

EDUCATION

MAY 2021 (ANTICIPATED)

FULL STACK FLEX CERTIFICATE, CARLETON UNIVERSITY

Anticipating completion in May 2021, program components covered to date include CSS, Javascript, jQuery and Node. Completed project examples:

• Cinco De Mayo Party Planner (Group Project)

Responsible for designing UI (using CSS) and programming the local storage function.

Deployed: https://www.kirsralk.github.io/APIGroupProject
Repository: https://www.github.com/kirsralk/APIGroupProject

Weather Dashboard (Solo Project)

Javascript and jQuery based app that uses APIs to search weather forecasts.

Deployed: https://www.kirsralk.github.io/APIWeatherDashboard
Repository: https://www.github.com/APIWeatherDashboard

SEPTEMBER 2020

CERTIFICATE IN FAMILY MEDIATION, YORK UNIVERSITY

• Currently pursuing AccFM designation

MAY 2015

JURIS DOCTOR, UNIVERSITY OF MANITOBA (ROBSON HALL)

- Joel & Lily Nitikman Entrance Scholarship
- Robson Hall Negotiation Competition Finalist

MAY 2012

HONOURS BACHELOR OF COMMERCE, LAKEHEAD UNIVERSITY

- First Class Standing
- Dual major concentrations in General Managements and Information Systems
- Minor concentration in Finnish Language

SKILLS

- Strong written and oral communication
- Extensive advocacy and public speaking experience
- Ability to work independently or as part of a team
- Remote work experience using the Slack and Zoom platforms